<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-15T14:33:02+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SwiftFoxx</title><subtitle>Practical articles on building modern apps with Swift and SwiftUI</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Everyday SwiftUI How-To’s</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/everyday-swift-how-tos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everyday SwiftUI How-To’s" /><published>2026-01-05T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2026-01-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/everyday-swift-how-tos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/everyday-swift-how-tos/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="everyday-swiftui-how-tos">Everyday SwiftUI How-To’s</h1>

<p>Jan 05, 2026 <span class="hashtag">General</span></p>

<p class="quote">The job of a developer or an engineer is not to write code. The job is to solve problems.</p>

<p class="mt-1"><img src="https://swiftfoxx.github.io/swiftblog-assets/images/posts/Cover%20Images/everyday.how.to.cover.png" alt="conver image" class="cover-image" /></p>

<p class="mt-2">SwiftUI is designed to be expressive, concise, and closely aligned with how UI is described. Most day-to-day development involves small, practical decisions: <em>layout adjustments, view visibility, styling, previews, and adapting to system appearance</em>.</p>

<p>This section brings together a set of <strong>focused how-to articles</strong> that address common SwiftUI tasks developers encounter while building real apps. Each post is scoped to a single problem and shows the most direct, idiomatic way to solve it using SwiftUI.</p>

<p>The topics here intentionally stay at the surface level:<br /></p>

<p>Centering views, applying padding selectively, reacting to color scheme changes, styling buttons, working with SF Symbols, and using previews effectively. These are not advanced concepts, but they are patterns you use constantly.</p>

<p>These articles act as practical references that you can read, code along, and refer to later.</p>

<p>This collection serves as a foundation for everything that follows—simple, repeatable solutions that keep SwiftUI layouts predictable, consistent, and aligned with system behavior.</p>

<hr class="mt-3" />

<div class="list mt-3">
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/all-about-creating-project-with-xcode/">
        <h4>All about creating a project with Xcode</h4>
        <p>Creating a project on Xcode is fairly simple but there are small nuances that do make a differnece.
        </p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/organize-files-boost-productivity/">
        <h4>Organize your files to boost productivity</h4>
        <p>Organizing folders and fies are important architectural decisions. Depending on the structure – MVC, MVVM, VIPER etc. – the file-folder structure changes. Just make sure it aids you more than it hurts you.</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/previewing-with-xcode/">
        <h4>The magical 'Preview' canvas</h4>
        <p>Previewing is not a new technology – it's long been used with frontend development. Let's dive deeper on how to minimize running the app by using the previews.</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/code-reusability/">
        <h4>How many ways are there to make a chunk of code reusable</h4>
        <p>In 2026, we can't engineer an app without reusability. It's scalable, customizable and saves a lot of time. But how many ways can we make something reusable?</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/customizing-buttons/">
        <h4>Buttons, did you say?</h4>
        <p>Let's customize the buttons, shall we?<br />Almost no designer uses the default button styles that Apple gives us and it takes ages to figure out the whats and hows. Let's get into buttons and actions.</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/get-view-to-center/">
        <h4>Get any view to the center</h4>
        <p>Centering a view can be tricky depending on the layout.</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/divider-with-custom-spacing/">
        <h4>How to add a divider with custom spacing</h4>
        <p>Dividers are essential to lists and large views displaying multiple sections. But can we customize them?</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/use-sf-symbols-correctly/">
        <h4>How to use SF Symbols correctly</h4>
        <p>SF Symbols pack thousands of icons that apps generally need. They are customizable in more ways than one and it's vast. Let's explore some of those.</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/support-dark-mode-properly/">
        <h4>How to support Dark Mode properly</h4>
        <p>Color scheme is handled by the system by default. But how to make it change on demand?</p>
    </a>
    <a class="element" href="/how-tos/build-settings-scene/">
        <h4><span class="highlight">Section Finale!</span> Let's build a settings scene.</h4>
        <p>Let's end this section of the blog by building a Settings scene using default and reusable components.</p>
    </a>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of practical, everyday SwiftUI how-tos covering common layout, styling, previews, and system behavior patterns used in real apps.]]></summary></entry></feed>